[Music]
hi everybody welcome back to the channel
and today we're going to do a nice Easy
Ice Cream using this
Milo so if you don't know what Milo is
it's it's a moled drink kind of along
the same lines as horx oval teen that
kind of thing uh I think it originated
in Australia and then went everywhere
very popular in many places around the
world all around Asia North America
they've got it you know so it's not that
popular in England but I think um
England has those HX and noal team
Brands let's get on this we're going to
do something here that we wouldn't
normally do and that is ignore the ice
cream stabilizer to a degree because in
the tests with this to get the flavor of
this cuz it's quite a mild flavor to get
a strong flavor of this this in your ice
cream you're going to need to use quite
a bit but it doesn't have a lot of milk
powder in it so we're going to need to
add some more milk powder to it so it's
going to throw your ice cream calculator
results out the window so ignore that
let's get over to the hob and get our
ingredients in the pan okay so we're
going to start with our dairy in the pan
and that is 450 gam of milk and 550 g of
whipping cream at
33% we're going to start to get that
warmed up and we've got two containers
here by as side one is our sugar with
our stabilizer in so we're just going to
give that a little mix so that's nicely
combined in with our
sugars and we're going to add that in
like so and then the other container has
our Milo which is this brown powder here
and our milk powder next to it so you
don't need to Mi mix together but hey
why not and we're going to add that into
our mix
too and all we're going to do now is get
our whisk and mix it all together we're
going to bring this up to 75 to 80° C
and we're going to leave it there for
about 20
minutes and then we'll come back and go
to the next step so the purpose of
keeping that base at 80° for 20 to 30
minutes is to evaporate some of the
excess water off Milo has a habit of
turning out quite thin so you really if
you're going to use a stabilizer got
something like Locust being gum in you
want to fully hydrate that and that's
how long it takes for Locust being gum
to completely hydrate it's about 30
minutes at 80 to 85c okay so that's that
purpose of that it will work with any
stabilizer you use so the longer you
heat it up or the the length of time you
heat it up helps helps evaporate some of
that excess moisture as well gives you a
slightly creamier result I think the
Bowl's a bit
small so with that said and done we're
going to get that into here and get that
into there and then we'll come back when
it's chilled to CH
[Music]
it okay the base been in
hours just cool enough you will get a
skin on top but it will just mix back in
so give it a a nice
[Music]
uh there we go thickened up nicely as
it's cooled down and we're going to pop
this in the machine to
[Music]
chain okay we're all done there's quite
a bit of sugar in this recipe so it will
take a little bit longer to churn if you
don't want that much sugar then you can
reduce the sugar content because this
has got quite a bit sugar in it and
that's what makes it a slow churner so
let's get some scooped up into our
container and we'll put it in the
[Music]
freezer one thing I am going to do is
take another tub I've got a little
leftover
amount of the graham
cracker biscuit
crumb good from the strawberry
cheesecake we're going to put that in
the tub as
well might as well experiment while
we're at
[Music]
it okay let's get that one in the
freezer
too
[Music]
so the next
day Milo ice cream is was definitely
invented in Australia and social media
shows gelato MSA has just posted about
this flavor so they sell it over there
there is a bit different there has
Brownie and I think caramel sauce in it
which sound really good sounds like a
really good combo but for now we're
going to
get one scooped up and see what this
tastes
[Music]
like so it Scoops really nicely as I
said this is slightly higher on the
sugar content a little bit more milk
powder because it can turn out a little
bit icy Scoops nice got a good texture
let's see what the flavors
[Music]
like
that's really good when I was making
these or this flavor the first version
was quite weak in
flavor and it became quite clear that it
needed more solids hence why there's
more milk powder in it but really nice
flavor it's warming it's very oval teeny
you know horx kind of flavor it's um MTT
is something that's quite with autumn
and winter but this would be really nice
you know with a nice hot drink next to
it as well so this version was really
good let's switch it over and do the one
with the cookie crumb
[Music]
in so again it's a really nice easy base
it's it's easy to scoop there not so
much sugar that it's kind of liquid
let's see what this gr cracker crust in
there
does that works really
well it's such a smooth ice cream this
one it's
uh it's got no
ice super smooth base nice and
flavorful and with that gr cracker crust
in there just adds another little
texture change to it
so excellent ice cream base
you could try what julan gulia did uh
with their brownies and caramel sauce
that would work really well with this
but you could also use HX or oine to do
the same thing whatever flavor you like
but as I've never had this before I
thought I'd give this one A bash really
successful very very happy with the
flavor the texture the scoop ability
straight out the freezer as well all
these things are just positive so very
very happy with this result hope you
give this one want to try thanks very
much for watching don't forget to like
And subscribe and I'll see you next
[Music]
week